## Fabio Papa – Full-Stack Web Developer

email: me@fabiopapa.dev mobile: +1 (778) 230-5559

web: https://www.fabiopapa.dev

fapapa

in fabio-papa-dev

### **Summary**

Software developer with over 16 years of experience in **full-stack** web development, with a strong focus on *Ruby on Rails*. Believes deeply in finding the simplest-possible solution, and iterating over it until an elegant, joy-eliciting solution emerges. Passionate about clean, readable code that communicates intent, *test-driven-* and *behavior-driven-design*, and natural user experiences.

### **Experience**

#### Software Developer, Animikii Inc.; remote — 2020-present

- Design, architect and implement major features—start-to-finish—in internal products and client projects using various versions of Rails and front-end languages and frameworks
- \* Proactively keep everyone informed with Agile, Scrum, Kanban, daily stand-ups
- Develop features for Niiwin, an internal Rails product that aids in building admin interfaces and developing other Rails apps
- ★ Lead developer on project for Canadian Red Cross, using Rails and Niiwin
- ★ Championed switching Git strategies company-wide to GitLab Flow to give the greatest flexibility with team size and CI/CD strategies
- Championed instituting a pull request template for all company repos to cheaply increase code quality and decrease code-review ping-pong
- Spearhead a collaborative project with First Nations Technology Council, leading five other developers in mentoring Indigenous youth
- \* Awarded ceremonial drum for being a team player, encouraging others, and exemplifying company values

#### Mentor, Lighthouse Labs; Vancouver, BC — 2020

- \* Assisted cohorts with debugging, code reviews, explanation, and exploration of programming topics
- \* Assessed student progress and identify students needing further attention
- Provided guidance to students as they pick and flesh-out their mid-term and final projects
- Nurtured students who were struggling, pin-pointing any foundational problems that were keeping them from learning new concepts, and devised plans for them to execute to get on-track
- ★ Led mock technical interviews to allow student to practice, and to further identify any holes in knowledge

Freelance Developer, Self-Employed; Coquitlam, BC — 2004-2019

- \* Architected and maintained Ruby on Rails applications
- \* Championed use of user stories with non-technical stakeholders
- ★ Spearheaded initiative to go from in-house physical deployment to AWS, Digital Ocean, and other cloud providers, reducing down-time and eliminating need to hire additional technical staff
- ★ Slashed deployment issues and time by integrating Docker containerization to equalize test/development/production environments
- Shortened feedback loop and development cycle using agile methodologies and continuous deployment
- ★ Implemented a test-first, behavior-driven design methodology

#### Owner/Franchisee, Mr. Pretzels; Vancouver, BC — 2016-2019

- ★ Owned and successfully managed three high-traffic locations
- ★ Implemented POS and digital signage infrastructure, allowing for remote updating of prices, synchronizing of menus across stores and effective lookup of real-time sales data
- ★ Procured a cloud-based software package to create and disseminate employee schedules, resulting in great reduction of under-/over-staffing and missed shifts, and increased employee satisfaction
- Reduced waste product and lost sales by writing software to be used by supervisors on location to calculate expected sales for remainder of day
- ★ Hired and managed employees, building a customer-centric culture

#### Procurement Specialist, Long View Systems; Vancouver, BC — 2015-2017

- \* Earned a place on the Cisco Procurement team in addition to General Procurement team through proven attention to detail and ability to manage time well
- ★ Collaborated with Account Managers, Project Managers, Consultants, manufacturers, logistics and more to successfully win and manage multi-million dollar deals
- Leveraged pricing programs, on-line technical resources and manufacturer experts to solve customers' business problems

#### **Skills**

#### Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, Python, Elixir, HTML, CSS

#### **Testing**

rSpec, Cucumber, FactoryBot, TimeCop, Mocha, Chai, Jest, Cypress, Storybook

# Frameworks && Libraries

Rails, Hotwire (Turbo, Stimulus), NodeJS, React, JQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, ActiveInteraction, Pundit, Devise, SASS, Docker, good grasp of HTTP request/response life-cycle

# Systems, CMS && Databases

SQL, Git, Subversion, AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Bundler, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, comfortable setting up domains and DNS records

#### **Education**

Lighthouse Labs, December 2019

Diploma of Web Development

Hebrew University of Jerusalem; Coursera, March 2019
Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris

Grade achieved: 98.4% average